Hale Family Papers, 1787-1988
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- HALE FAMILY
  - Generation III
    - Hale, Edward Everett (1822-1909)
      - Speeches and writings
        - Writings
          - Business/financial materials
            - Dana Estes and Co., 1899-1905 (Box 42, Folder 10)
            - Dodd, Mead and Co., 1903-09 (Box 42, Folder 11)
            - Fields, Osgood and Co., 1869-74 (Box 42, Folder 12)
            - Funk and Wagnalls, 1883-1907 (Box 42, Folder 13-14)
            - G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1886-1910 (Box 42, Folder 15)
            - Ginn and Co., 1887-1909 (Box 42, Folder 16)
            - H.M. Caldwell Co., 1896-1905 (Box 42, Folder 17)
            - Harper and Brothers, 1881-1909 (Box 42, Folder 18)
            - Henry O. Shepard Publishing Co., 1894 (Box 42, Folder 19)
            - Houghton, Mifflin and Co., 1888-1910 (Box 42, Folder 20)
            - J. Stillman Smith and Co., 1896-97 (Box 42, Folder 21)
            - James R. Osgood Co., 1869, 1876 (Box 42, Folder 22)
            - Library of Congress, Copyright Office, 1876-1906, undated (Box 43, Folder 1-2)
            - Lamson, Wolffe and Co., 1895-99 (Box 43, Folder 3)
            - Little, Brown and Co., 1898-1909 (Box 43, Folder 4-5)
            - Lothrop Publishing Co., 1893-1909 (Box 43, Folder 6)
            - The Macmillan Co., 1905-09 (Box 43, Folder 7)
            - The Outlook Co., 1897-1907, undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
            - Porter and Coates, 1887-91 (Box 43, Folder 9)
            - Rand and Avery, 1865-68 (Box 43, Folder 10)
            - Roberts Brothers, 1871-99 (Box 43, Folder 11-13)
            - Thomas Y. Crowell and Co., 1897-99 (Box 43, Folder 14)
            - Walker, Wise and Co., 1860-66 (Box 43, Folder 15)
            - Correspondence with editors re: permission to reprint, anthologize, etc., 1888-1901, undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
            - Correspondence with attorneys
              - Foster, Roger, 1888-98 (Box 43, Folder 17)
              - Tyndale, Theodore, 1894-99, undated (Box 43, Folder 18)
            - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 43, Folder 19)
            - Financial journal, 1877-1909 (Box 43, Folder 20)
          - Volumes
            - Boys' Heros. (Boston: D. Lothrop Company, 1886) (Box 43)
            - Christmas in Narragansett. (New York and London: Funk & Wagnalls, 1884) (Box 43)
            - Easter: a collection for a hundred friends. (Boston: J. Stilman Smith & Company, 1886) (Box 43)
            - Every-day Sermons. (Boston: J. Stilman Smith & Company, 1892) (Box 43)
            - For Christmas and New Year privately printed for the holidays, 1906 (Box 43)
            - For Fifty Years: Verses written on occasion, in the course of the nineteenth century. (Boston: Roberts Brothers, 1893) (Box 43)
            - The Fortunes of Rachel. (NY: Funk and Wagnalls, 1884) (Box 43)
            - History of the United States written for the Chautauqua Reading Circles (New York: Chautauqua Press, 1884) (Box 43)
            - How They Lived in Hampton. A Story of Practical Christianity Applied in the Manufacture of Woolens. (Boston: J. Stilman Smith & Co., 1888) (Box 43)
            - How To Do It. (Boston: Roberts Brothers, 1884) (Box 43)
            - How To Live. (Boston: Little, Brown, and Company, 1903) (Box 43)
            - James Russell Lowell and his friends. (Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin and Company, 1899) (Box 43)
            - June to May: The Sermons of a Year preached at South Congregational Church in Boston, in 1880 and 1881. (Boston: Roberts Brothers, 1881) (Box 43)
            - The Man Without a Country (Boston: Roberts Brothers, 1889 and Boston: J. Stilman Smith & Co., 1891) (Box 43)
            - The Man Without a Country and Other Tales. (Boston: R. B. Palfrey, 1868) (Box 43)
            - Mohonk Addresses by Edward Everett Hale and David J. Brewer with an introduction by Edwin H. Mead. Published for the International School of Peace. (Boston: Ginn and Company, 1910) (Box 43)
            - My Friend the Boss: A Story of To-day. (Boston: J. Stilman Smith & Company, 1888) (Box 43)
            - A New England Boyhood. (New York: Cassell Publishing Co., 1893) (Box 43)
            - New England History in Ballads by Edward Everett Hale and his children with a few additions by other people. Illustrated by Ellen D. Hale, Philip L. Hale, and Lilian Hale. (Boston: Little, Brown, and Company, 1903) (Box 43)
            - Our Christmas in a Palace. A Traveller's Story. (NY: Funk and Wagnalls, 1883) (Box 43)
            - Our Christmas in a Palace (NY: Standard Library, 1884) (Box 43)
            - Prayers in the Senate: Prayers offered in the Senate of the United States in the Winter Session of 1904. (Boston: Little, Brown, and Company, 1904) (Box 43)
            - Ralph Waldo Emerson together with two early essays of Emerson. (Boston: Brown & Company, 1899) (Box 43)
            - Stories of Invention told by inventors and their friends. (Boston: Roberts Brothers, 1885) (Box 43)
            - The Story of Massachusetts (Boston: D. Lothrop Company, 1891) (Box 43)
            - Sunday-school Stories on the Golden Texts of the International Lessons of 1889. (Boston: Roberts Brothers, 1889) (Box 43)
            - Sunday-school Stories on the Golden Texts of the International Lessons of 1889. Second part. (Boston: Roberts Brothers, 1889) (Box 43)
            - Tell It Again series (Boston: J. Stilman Smith & Company) Aunt Caroline's Present, 1895
              - Col. Clipsham's Calendar, 1895 (Box 43)
              - Hands Off (2 copies), 1895 (Box 43)
              - One Good Turn: A Story, 1893 (Box 43)
              - A Safe Deposit, 1895 (Box 43)
            - Ten Times One is Ten: The Possible Reformation. (Boston: Roberts Brothers, 1871) (Box 43)
            - The Works of Edward Everett Hale, Library Edition (Boston: Little, Brown, and Company) Ten Times One is Ten and Other Stories, 1899 (Box 43)
              - Vol. II, In His Name and Christmas Stories, 1899 (Box 43)
              - Vol. IV, The Brick Moon and Other Stories, 1899 (Box 43)
              - Vol. V, Philip Nolan's Friends: A Story of the Change of Western Empire, 1899 (Box 43)
              - Vol. VI, A New England Boyhood and other bits of autobiography, 1900 (Box 43)
              - Vol. VII, How To Do It to which is added How To Live, 1900 (Box 43)
              - Vol. VIII, Addresses and Essays on Subjects of History, Education, and Government, 1900 (Box 43)
              - Vol. X, Poems and Fancies (Box 43)
        - Edited by Edward Everett Hale
          - The Age of Chivalry or Legends of King Arthur by Thomas Bulfinch. A new enlarged and revised edition by Edward E. Hale. (Boston: S.W. Tilton & Co., 1884) (Box 43)
          - Lend a Hand: A Journal of Organized Philanthropy. Volume I, 1886. (Boston: Lend a Hand Publishing Company) (Box 43)
          - Lend a Hand: A Journal of Organized Philanthropy. Volume II, 1887. (Boston: Lend a Hand Publishing Company) (Box 43)
          - Standard Biographies: Lights of Two Centuries. (New York and Chicago: A.S. Barnes and Company, 1887) (Box 43)
      - Miscellaneous
        - The Eath and Its Story: a First Book of Geology by Angelo Heilprin with inscription to Harriet E. Freeman (Box 44)
    - Hale, Emily (Perkins) (1829-1914) [Mrs. Edward Everett Hale]
      - Biographical material and memorabilia
        - General, 1852-1905, undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
        - Cookbook and recipes, circa 1873 (Box 44, Folder 2)
        - Estate, 1911-15 (Box 44, Folder 3)
        - Financial, 1902-11 (Box 44, Folder 4)
        - Social Register, Boston and Washington, DC, 1910 (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Baldwin, Elizabeth(?) [cousin], undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
        - Hale groups, 1889-1908 (Box 45, Folder 2-6)
        - Hale, Arthur [son], 1877-1912 (Box 45, Folder 7)
        - Hale, Edward Everett [husband]
          - 1868-99 (Box 45, Folder 8-25)
          - 1900-08, undated (Box 46, Folder 1-5)
        - Hale, Edward Everett [husband] and Ellen Day [daughter], 1891-1906 (Box 46, Folder 6)
        - Hale, Edward Everett, Jr. [son], 1875, 1886 (Box 46, Folder 7)
        - Hale, Ellen Day [daughter]
          - 1864-Mar 1892 (Box 46, Folder 8-20)
          - Apr 1892-1905 (Box 47, Folder 1-16)
          - 1906-12, undated (Box 48, Folder 1-3)
        - Hale, Lilian (Westcott) [daughter-in-law], 1902-13 (Box 48, Folder 4)
        - Hale, Nancy [granddaughter], 1911 (Box 48, Folder 5)
        - Hale, Philip Leslie [son], 1878, 1898 (?) (Box 48, Folder 6)
        - Perkins, Mary [mother](from Europe), 1856-57, 1889 (Box 48, Folder 7)
        - Miscellaneous, 1872-1912 (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, incoming, 1873-1913, undated (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Hale, Lucretia Peabody (1820-1900)
      - Biographical material and memorabilia
        - General, 1916, 1967, undated (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Cookbook, undated (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - Embroidery
          - Sampler (age 10), 1830 (Box 49, Folder 3)
          - Designs and work samples, circa 1870s (Box 49, Folder 4-5)
        - Estate, 1897-98 (Box 49, Folder 6)
        - Memorabilia, undated (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        [Typescripts of selected letters are in separate folders filed after the originals]
        - Bates, Mr., 1883 (Box 49, Folder 7a)
        - Everett, William, 1863-96, undated (Box 49, Folder 8)
        - Hale groups, 1847-76, undated (Box 49, Folder 9-11)
        - Hale, Alexander "Elly" [brother], 1848-50 (Box 49, Folder 12-13)
        - Hale, Charles [brother]
          - 1848-63 (Box 49, Folder 14-19)
          - 1864-76, undated (Box 50, Folder 1-15)
        - Hale, Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) [brother and sister-in-law]
          - 1837-53 (Box 50, Folder 16-27)
          - 1854-96 (Box 51, Folder 1-33)
          - 1897-99, undated (Box 52, Folder 1-3)
        - Hale, Ellen Day [niece], 1856, 1862, undated (Box 52, Folder 4)
        - Hale, Nathan, Jr. [brother], 1837-70, undated (Box 52, Folder 5-6)
        - Hale, Nathan, Sr. [father], 1850 (Box 52, Folder 7)
        - Hale, Robert Beverly "Robbie" [nephew], undated (Box 52, Folder 8)
        - Hale, Sarah Everett [sister], 1835-51 (Box 52, Folder 9-16)
        - Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett) [mother]
          - 1838-55 (Box 52, Folder 17-30)
          - 1856-66, undated (Box 53, Folder 1-7)
        - Hale, Susan [sister], 1840-68, undated (Box 53, Folder 8-15)
        - Fragments, undated (Box 53, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence, incoming, 1886-88, undated (Box 53, Folder 17)
      - Writings
        - Diary, 1867(?)-68(?) (Box 53, Folder 18)
        - General, 1911, 1968, undated (Box 53, Folder 19)
        - "The Peterkins at the 'Carnival of Authors'": notebook, undated (Box 53, Folder 20)
        - "The Queen of the Red Chessmen," with "Miss Lucinda" by Rose Terry. (NY: The Happy Hour Library, undated) (Box 53, Folder 21)
        - Volumes
          - Familien Peterkin (Gyldendal, 1969) [Danish edition of The Peterkin Papers] (Box 53)
          - The Peterkin Papers. (Boston: James R. Osgood & Co., 1880) (Box 53)
          - The Peterkin Papers. (Boston and NY: Houghton, Mifflin and Co., 1900) (Box 53)
          - Stories for Children. Containing Simple Lessons in Morals. A Supplementary Reader for Schools or for Use at Home. (Boston and NY: Leach, Shewell & Sanborn, 1892) (Box 53)
    - Hale, Nathan, Jr. (1818-71)
      - Biographical material and memorabilia
        - Artwork, undated (Box 54, Folder 1)
        - Commonplace book and memorabilia, 1836 (Box 54, Folder 2)
        - Estate, 1871 (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Hale groups, 1851-69, undated (Box 54, Folder 4)
        - Hale, Charles [brother], 1852-69, undated (Box 54, Folder 5-7)
        - Hale, Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) [brother and sister-in-law], 1831-70, undated (Box 55, Folder 1-7)
        - Hale, Ellen Day [niece], 1864(?) (Box 55, Folder 8)
        - Hale, Lucretia Peabody [sister], 1838-70 (Box 55, Folder 9-10)
        - Hale, Nathan, Sr. [father], 1838-54 (Box 55, Folder 11)
        - Hale, Sarah Everett [sister], 1834-50, undated (Box 55, Folder 12-13)
        - Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett) [mother], 1835(?)-65 (Box 55, Folder 14-20)
        - Hale, Susan [sister], 1854-69 (Box 55, Folder 21)
        - Fragments, undated (Box 55, Folder 22)
        - Non-family, 1842-69, undated (Box 55, Folder 23)
      - Correspondence, incoming
        - Hawthorne, Nathaniel, undated (Box 55, Folder 24)
        - Story, William Wetmore, 1851 (Box 55, Folder 25)
        - Sumner, Charles, undated (Box 55, Folder 26)
        - Publishers, 1843, 1869 (Box 55, Folder 27)
      - Writings
        - Diaries, trips, 1841-48, 1860 (Box 55, Folder 28)
        - Miscellaneous, 1832-49, undated (Box 55, Folder 29)
    - Hale, Sarah Everett (1817-1851)
      - Bible, 1840 (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - "Extract Book": commonplace book, circa 1827-50 (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Everett, Alexander Hill [uncle], 1842 (Box 57, Folder 1)
        - Everett, Charlotte (Brooks) [aunt], 1844-45, undated (Box 57, Folder 2)
        - Everett, Lucretia (Peabody) [aunt], 1846-51 (Box 57, Folder 3)
        - Hale groups, 1846-48 (Box 57, Folder 4)
        - Hale, Alexander "Elly" [brother], 1845-50 (Box 57, Folder 5-6)
        - Hale, Charles, 1848-49 (Box 57, Folder 7)
        - Hale, Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) [brother and sister-in-law], 1835-51 (Box 57, Folder 8-15)
        - Hale, Lucretia Peabody [sister], 1837-51 (Box 57, Folder 16-19)
        - Hale, Nathan, Jr. [brother], 1836-49 (Box 57, Folder 20-24)
        - Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett) [mother], 1838-51 (Box 57, Folder 25-28)
        - Hale, Susan [sister], 1838-50 (Box 57, Folder 29)
      - Correspondence, incoming: Channing, M., 1840? (Box 57, Folder 30)
      - Writings, miscellaneous, 1827, 1829 (Box 57, Folder 31)
    - Hale, Susan (1833-1910)
      - Biographical materials and memorabilia
        - General, 1892-1984, undated (Box 58, Folder 1)
        - Memorabilia, 1862-1901 (Box 58, Folder 2)
        - Readings and skits, 1890, undated (Box 58, Folder 3)
      - Artwork
        [See also Oversize Materials]
        - Sketches, 1840-63, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
        - Watercolors
          - Miscellaneous, 1864-86, undated (Box 58, Folder 5-6)
          - Wildflowers of the Holy Land, 1868 (Box 58, Folder 7)
        - Sketchbooks
          - 1863 (Box 58, Folder 8)
          - (landscapes)1865 (Box 59, Folder 1)
          - (Egypt)1868, 1887, undated (Box 59, Folder 2)
          - (flowers)undated (Box 59, Folder 3)
          - (miscellaneous)undated (Box 59, Folder 4)
          - (landscapes)undated (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Church, E.A., 1903-06 (Box 59, Folder 6)
        - Hale groups, 1842-57, 1868-1910 (Box 59, Folder 7-12)
        - Hale, Alexander "Elly" [brother], 1849-50 (Box 59, Folder 13)
        - Hale, Charles [brother]
          - 1846-60 (Box 59, Folder 14-15)
          - 1861-81, undated (Box 60, Folder 1-8)
        - Hale, Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) [brother and sister-in-law], 1842?-1907 (Box 60, Folder 9-17)
        - Hale, Edward Everett, Jr. [nephew], 1879-90 (Box 60, Folder 18-20)
        - Hale, Ellen Day [niece], 1868-1910, undated (Box 61, Folder 1-13)
        - Hale, Herbert Dudley [nephew], 1875, 1892 (Box 61, Folder 14)
        - Hale, Lucretia Peabody [sister]
          - 1847-73, 1876-80 (Box 61, Folder 15-22)
          - 1881-96 (Box 62, Folder 1-16)
          - 1897-1901, undated (Box 63, Folder 1-3)
        - Hale, Nathan, Sr. [father], 1850 (Box 63, Folder 4)
        - Hale, Nathan, Jr. [brother], 1853-70, undated (Box 63, Folder 5)
        - Hale, Philip Leslie [nephew] and Lilian (Westcott), 1885-1902 (Box 63, Folder 6)
        - Hale, Sarah Everett [sister], 1842-50, undated (Box 63, Folder 7)
        - Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett) [mother], 1847-68 (Box 63, Folder 8-12)
        - Unidentified fragments, undated (Box 63, Folder 13)
        - Miscellaneous, 1868-1910 (Box 63, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence, incoming, 1872, 1890-91 (Box 63, Folder 15)
      - Writings
        - Diary
          - 1889 (Box 63, Folder 16)
          - 1890-91 (Box 63, Folder 17)
        - "The Emblem: A Mystic Romance" ms. of Ch. I, "The Gloomy Chamber," undated (Box 63, Folder 18)
        - "The Novel of the Nile" written by Charles, Lucretia, and Susan Hale on Nile trip, 1867-68: manuscript (Box 63, Folder 19-27)
        - "The Press": ms., undated (Box 63, Folder 28)
        - "What the Owl Saw in the Woods," undated (Box 63, Folder 29)
        - Royalty statements, 1888-1904 (Box 63, Folder 30)
        - Volumes
          - A Family Flight Around Home. Part Second by Edward Everett Hale and Susan Hale (Boston: D. Lothrop Company, 1884) (Box 63)
          - Letters of Susan Hale edited by Caroline P. Atkinson with an introduction by Edward Everett Hale. (Boston: Marshall Jones Company, 1919) (Box 63)
  - Generation IV
    - Hale, Arthur (1859-1939)
      - General, 1880-1903, undated (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Hale groups, 1872-1931 (Box 64, Folder 2)
        - Hale, Edward Everett [father]
          - 1872-92 (Box 64, Folder 3-22)
          - 1897-1909, undated (Box 65, Folder 1-9)
        - Hale, Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) [parents], 1872-1904, undated (Box 65, Folder 10)
        - Hale, Edward Everett, Jr. [brother], 1875-78 (Box 65, Folder 11)
        - Hale, Ellen Day [sister]
          - 1872-1917 (Box 65, Folder 12-22)
          - 1918-39, undated (Box 66, Folder 1-10)
        - Hale, Emily (Perkins) [mother]
          - 1872-92 (Box 66, Folder 11-19)
          - 1893-1913, undated (Box 67, Folder 1-6)
        - Hale, Herbert Dudley [brother], 1875-82 (Box 67, Folder 7)
        - Hale, Philip Leslie [brother], 1883-1914 (Box 67, Folder 8)
        - Hale, Robert Beverly [brother], 1883-94 (Box 67, Folder 9)
        - Miscellaneous, 1872-1935, undated (Box 67, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, incoming, 1877-1938, undated (Box 67, Folder 11)
      - Writings: poems, 1859-1939 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Hale, Camilla (Conner) [Mrs. Arthur]: letters to Hales, undated (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Hale, Charles Alexander (1861-67): letters to Ellen Day Hale, 1867 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Hale, Edward Everett, Jr. (1863-1932) "Jack"
      - Biographical materials and memorabilia
        - General, 1873, 1883-1972, undated (Box 68, Folder 1)
        - Clippings re: campaign for Congress, 1912 (Box 68, Folder 2)
        - Artwork, circa 1868, undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
        - Notes, undated (Box 68, Folder 4)
        - The Union College I Remember, 1902-46 by Charles Newman Waldron (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Crane, Stephen (photocopy), 1895 (Box 68, Folder 6)
        - Hale, Arthur [brother], 1904, 1926 (Box 68, Folder 7)
        - Hale, Edward Everett [father]
          - 1872-99 (Box 68, Folder 8-13)
          - 1900-09, undated (Box 69, Folder 1-4)
        - Hale, Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) [parents], 1873-1908 (Box 69, Folder 5)
        - Hale, Ellen Day [sister]
          - 1879-1932, undated (Box 69, Folder 6-16)
          - undated (Box 70, Folder 1-2)
        - Hale, Emily (Perkins) [mother], 1873-1914, undated (Box 70, Folder 3-14)
        - Hale, Herbert Dudley [brother], 1880, undated (Box 70, Folder 15)
        - Hale, Lilian (Westcott) [sister-in-law], 1902, 1931-32 (Box 70, Folder 16)
        - Hale, Nancy [niece], 1928-29 (Box 70, Folder 17)
        - Hale, Philip Leslie [brother], 1927 (Box 70, Folder 18)
        - Miscellaneous, 1884, 1904, undated (Box 70, Folder 19)
      - Writings: Life of Edward Everett Hale: correspondence, notes, 1919, undated (Box 70, Folder 20)
    - Hale, Rose (Perkins) (1866-1963) [Mrs. Edward Everett Hale, Jr.]
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Hale, Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) [parents-in-law], 1893-94, 1904, undated (Box 70, Folder 21)
        - Hale, Ellen Day [sister-in-law], 1919 (Box 70, Folder 22)
        - Hale, Lilian (Westcott) [sister-in-law], 1917 (Box 70, Folder 23)
    - Hale, Ellen Day, Lilian (Westcott) Hale, and Philip Leslie Hale
      - Artwork: letters to Nancy Hale, 1968-88 (Box 71, Folder 1-2)
        [See also Hale, Ellen Day: Artwork; Hale, Philip Leslie: Artwork; and Hale, Lilian Westcott: Artwork; and Oversize Materials]
    - Hale, Ellen Day (1855-1940)
      - Biographical materials and memorabilia
        - General and miscellaneous, 1788, 1886-1949, undated (Box 71, Folder 3)
        - Memberships, 1905-19 (Box 71, Folder 4)
        - Memorabilia, 1862-1909, undated (Box 71, Folder 5-6)
        - Papers at Archives of American Art, 1978 (Box 71, Folder 7)
        - Will, 1936-37 (Box 71, Folder 8)
        - Estate, 1937-41 (Box 71, Folder 9)
      - Artwork
        - Correspondence
          - 1877-1934, undated (Box 71, Folder 10)
          - to Nancy Hale, 1967-88, undated (Box 71, Folder 11)
          - Re: gift of self portrait to Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1987-88 (Box 71, Folder 12)
        - Clippings and memorabilia, 1878-95, undated (Box 71, Folder 13)
        - Exhibitions
          - Richard York Gallery, Oct-Nov 1981: correspondence, catalog (Box 71, Folder 14)
          - "American Women Artists, 1830-1930": correspondence and clippings, 1986 (Box 71, Folder 15)
          - Dickinson College, 2007 (Box 71, Folder 15a)
        - Lists, 1930, undated (Box 71, Folder 16)
        - Photographs, 1981, undated (Box 71, Folder 17)
        - Sketches, etching, oil, watercolors, 1892, undated (Box 71, Folder 18)
      - Activities
        - General correspondence
          - 1902-32, undated (Box 71, Folder 19)
          - With attorney George Lemist Clark, 1909-15 (Box 71, Folder 20-22)
          - Responses to advertisement to find a place for a maid, 1918 (Box 72, Folder 1)
          - School finances for Laura Hale, 1927 (Box 72, Folder 2)
        - Copyrights, Edward Everett Hale and Lucretia Peabody Hale
          - General, 1910-37 (Box 72, Folder 3)
          - Little, Brown & Co., 1910-37, undated (Box 72, Folder 4)
        - Evelyn Nordhoff Bindery
          - General, 1899-1901, undated (Box 72, Folder 5)
          - Correspondence, 1898-1902, undated (Box 72, Folder 6-7)
          - Talk re: Evelyn Nordhoff given to Social Reform Club, 1899 (Box 72, Folder 8)
        - Family papers and artifacts
          - General, 1910-33 (Box 72, Folder 9)
          - Clementi piano, 1932-33, undated (Box 72, Folder 10)
          - Egyptian artifacts, 1931, 1965, undated (Box 72, Folder 11)
          - Library of Congress, Manuscript Division, 1931-34 (Box 72, Folder 12)
          - Madigan, Thomas re: autograph collection, 1932-33 (Box 72, Folder 13)
          - New York State Library re: Edward Everett Hale diaries, 1933 (Box 72, Folder 14)
        - Financial
          - General, 1879-1936, undated (Box 72, Folder 15)
        - Grant from American Unitarian Association, 1936 (Box 72, Folder 16)
        - Helen Knowlton Subscription Fund: correspondence, 1897 (Box 72, Folder 17)
        - Real Estate/houses
          - General, 1908-19, undated (Box 72, Folder 18)
          - Correspondence with Gasch & Birge/Herman E. Gasch, 1907-36, undated (Box 72, Folder 19)
          - Folly Cove, Rockport/Gloucester, MA, property
            - General, 1910-37, undated (Box 72, Folder 20)
            - Correspondence with attorney Frederick H. Tarr, 1910-32 (Box 72, Folder 21)
        - William Morris Hunt Memorial Fund
          - General re: William Morris Hunt, 1879-1982 (Box 72, Folder 22)
          - Correspondence, 1879-98, undated (Box 72, Folder 23)
          - Records, 1880, undated (Box 72, Folder 24)